Sudhakar Annadurai

Toronto, ON | +1 437 662 3334 | asudhakar@live.in | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sudhakarannadurai

SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with 8+ years of web and mobile development experience. Proven leader and mentor with a passion for open source software, blockchain, devops, and startups. Seeking a challenging and rewarding position in a fast-paced environment with the opportunity to make a significant impact.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Technical Skills: GoLang, Node JS, React Native, Laravel, PHP, MySQL, pgSQL, JavaScript, Flutter, Postgress, Kafka

Infra & Others: Docker, k8s, CI/CD, Linux, Shell Scripting, Ansible, Agile, TDD, DDD, Microservices

Cloud Providers: AWS, Azure, Digital Ocean

WORK EXPERIENCE

Thoughtworks Chennai, India

Software Consultant Sep 2019 - Jun 2023

- Managed and Developed customized software solutions for diverse clients, including banks, startups, and Fortune
 500 companies, implementing Domain Driven Design principles to restructure the code base. This resulted in a 30% decrease in development time and increased code maintainability.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define project scope and requirements, resulting in an on-time delivery of the systems within a year timeline.
- Developed and implemented an automated CI/CD pipeline for a software development team, resulting in a 50% reduction in deployment time and a 75% decrease in the number of production incidents.
- Led and managed a team of 5 developers to successfully design and implement Loan Origination System and Loan Management System, utilizing microservices architecture and Event-Driven Design principles.
- Conducted in-depth workshops on implementing domain driven design principles to a team of 20 software engineers, resulting in a 30% increase in code quality and a reduction of bugs by 25%.

Indusnet Technologies Chennai, India

Software Developer

Dec 2018 - Sep 2019

- Managed all aspects of the software development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to deployment, ensuring ontime delivery of high-quality web applications.
- Designed and implemented a user-friendly internal tool for a government organization, streamlining the tracking of real estate projects, agents, and complaints using Laravel.
- Developed an automated reporting feature that reduced manual data entry by 75%, resulting in increased efficiency and time savings.
- Managed a team of 5 developers to successfully complete the entire development lifecycle of threra, delivering the project on time and within budget.

Revmakx Technologies Chennai, India

Software Developer

Sep 2015 - Mar 2016

- Developed and implemented internal applications for streamlined workflow processes, resulting in a 20% increase in team productivity.
- Created and maintained a self-hosted application to manage multiple WordPress sites in a single dashboard, later adopted by over 300,000 WordPress sites.
- Successfully rolled out a feature to install InfiniteWP in different platforms, such as installing from a plugin, installing to cPanel, and manual installation.
- Deployed and managed continuous integration and deployment pipelines for the internal monolith application, reducing deployment time by 75%.

Greefi Technologies Salem, India

Founder Mar 2016 - Dec 2018

- Developed and launched a portfolio of 10 web and mobile applications using Laravel, PHP, Node.JS, React Native, Bootstrap, and CI/CD containers, resulting in a 20% increase in client satisfaction.
- Managed and mentored a team of five interns, providing guidance and effectively delegating tasks to ensure timely
 project delivery.
- Built a robust client network through proactive networking efforts, leading to a 30% increase in business opportunities.

EDUCATION

Anna University Chennai, India

Bachelors in Computer Science

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

GXS - Singapore Bank Remote

Senior Consultant - GoLang

Nov 2021 - Jun 2023

Graduation Date: Jun 2015

 I applied Event-Driven Design principles to create a Loan Management System, reducing loan processing time by 20%. I designed and deployed the cb-sg-adapter using Golang, gRPC, Kafka, and AWS. Utilizing TDD and tools like Datadog, I ensured reliability. The system employed microservices, Docker, and K8s for scalability. GitLab Pipeline facilitated automation.

Foodpanda Remote

Senior Consultant - Golang

Mar 2021 - Oct 2021

I established a GraphQL federated gateway, improving system efficiency by 20%. I collaborated on deploying a
vendor microservice for seamless integration, and optimized data retrieval, boosting efficiency by 20% and cutting
retrieval time by 30%. Tools included Golang, GraphQL, Datadog, Kafka, TDD, go-micro, AWS, Docker, K8s, and
Microservices.

IDFC Bank Mumbai, India

Consultant - Golang

Oct 2019 - Mar 2021

• In the Payments and Assisted Call services team, I managed UPI and Fund Transfer Flow using GoLang, React Native, and ReactJS. I developed APIs for front-end, integrated with core banking, and utilized tools like Oracle, Redis, Kafka, and AWS for seamless transactions.

TNRERA Chennai, India

Senior Software Developer

2018 - 2019

• I developed a user-friendly portal for real estate agents, cutting processing time by 40%. Collaborating cross-functionally, I boosted productivity by 30% by addressing document scrutiny challenges. Integration of data analytics tools lowered errors by 25%. Employed PHP, Laravel, Payment Integration, and Docker.